Guide to the Entitled Opinions (About Life and Literature) with Robert Harrison
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Entitled opinions (about life and literature) with Robert Harrison
2005-2013
SC1089
Harrison, Robert Pogue.
6615.04 megabyte(s) (169 computer files)
The materials consist of program audiorecordings of Robert Harrison's show "Entitled opions (about life and literature)" broadcast on KZSU 90.1 Wednesdays from 2-3PM.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Robert Pogue Harrison, the Rosina Pierotti Professor in Italian Literature at Stanford, hosts a weekly literary talk show on KZSU (Stanford's radio station), typically a one-on-one conversation with a special guest.
Description of the Collection
The materials consist of program audiorecordings of Robert Harrison's show "Entitled Opions (about life and literature)" broadcast on KZSU 90.1 Wednesdays from 2-3PM, in which Professor Robert Harrison interviews guests about issues that range from literature and philosophy to politics and sports. Past guests have included Nobel laureate Orhan Pamuk, Paul R. Ehrlich, Richard Rorty, Vinton Cerf, Shirley Hazzard, Colm Toibin, Andrei Linde, Marjorie Perloff, Rene Girard, Michel Serres, Kathleen Sullivan, Gwyneth Lewis, Tobias Wolff and many others.
Access Terms
Girard, Rene, 1923-; Gumbrecht, Hans Ulrich.; Harrison, Robert Pogue.; Mudimbe-boyi, M. Elizabeth.; Perloff, Marjorie.; Rorty, Richard.; Schnapp, Jeffrey T. (Jeffrey Thompson), 1954-; Serres, Michel.; American literature--20th century.; Art --Study and teaching.; Art and literature; Art and literature--United States--History--20th century; Art criticism.; Art, Modern; Comparative literature--Study and teaching.; English literature--Study and teaching.; European literature--Study and teaching.; French literature--Study and teaching; German literature--Study and teaching.; Literature, Modern--History and criticism; Modernism (Literature)
Collection Contents
- Program Audio
  - Anti-Americanism - A conversation with Russell Berman, 2005 Apr 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A conversation with Laura Wittman about Michel Tournier's Friday, 2005 Sep 14; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A conversation with René Girard about his theory of mimetic desire, 2005 Sep 17; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Athletic Beauty - A conversation with Hans Ulrich Gumbrecht in praise of athletic beauty, 2005 Sep 17; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Robert Harrison on KQED 88.5 "Forum with Michael Krazny", 2005 Sep 20; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Enlightenment - A conversation w Dan Edelstein, 2005 Sep 28; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A conversation with Professor René Girard about ritual, myth, and religion, 2005 Oct 4; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Scapegoat - A conversation with Rene Girard, 2005 Oct 4; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Epicureanism - A conversation with Andrea Nightingale, 2005 Oct 8; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Francophonie - A conversation with Elisabeth Boyi, 2005 Oct 11; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Martin Heidegger - A conversation with Andrew Mitchell, 2005 Oct 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Virgil - A conversation with Susanna Braund, 2005 Oct 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Marcel Proust - A conversation with Joshua Landy, 2005 Nov 1; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Ezra Pound - A conversation with Marjorie Perloff, 2005 Nov 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Richard Rorty - A conversation, 2005 Nov 22; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Crowds - A conversation with Jeffrey Schnapp, 2005 Nov 29; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Albert Camus - A conversation with Jean-Marie Apostolides, 2005 Dec 6; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Vladamir Nabokov - A conversation with Monika Greenleaf, 2005 Dec 13; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Michel Serres - A conversation (in French), 2005 Dec 20; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Shirley Hazzard - A conversation, 2006 Jan 10; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Cosmology - A conversation with Andrei Linde, 2006 Jan 17; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Henry David Thoreau - A conversation with Kathryn Todd, 2006 Jan 24; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Historical Jesus - A conversation with Thomas Sheehan, 2006 Jan 31; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Man Without Qualities - A conversation with Hans Ulrich Gumbrecht, 2006 Feb 7; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Isaac Babel - A conversation with Gregory Freidin, 2006 Feb 14; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Fate of the Earth - A conversation with Paul Ehrlich, 2006 Feb 21; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - American Cemeteries - A conversation Marilyn Yalom, 2006 Feb 28; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - 1910 - A conversation with Thomas Harrison, 2006 Mar 7; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Love Poetry - A conversation with Lisa Dornell, 2006 Mar 14; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The History of the Book - A conversation with Seth Lerer, 2006 Apr 4; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Americans in Paris - A conversation with Cecile Alduy, 2006 Apr 11; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Resurrection pt 1 - A conversation with Tom Sheehan, 2006 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Resurrection pt 2 - A conversation with Tom Sheehan, 2006 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The US Constitution - A conversation with Kathleen Sullivan, 2006 May 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Avantgarde - A conversation with Marjorie Perloff, 2006 May 9; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Cancer - Part 2 of a conversation with Dr. Michael Hendrickson, 2006 May 16; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Life - Part 1 of a conversation with Dr. Michael Hendrickson, 2006 May 16; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Virgin Mary - A conversation with Bissera Pentcheva, 2006 May 23; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - American Corporations - A conversation with Drew Gibson, 2006 May 30; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Henry James - A conversation with Colm Toibin, 2006 Jun 6; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A monologue on birds and concluding opinions from Robert Harrison., 2006 Jun 13; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Concluding Opinions, 2006 Jun 13; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A post-avian epilogue on consumerism and the earthly paradise, 2006 Jun 20; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Dante Pt. 1 - A Conversation with Rachel Jacoff, 2007 Apr 10; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Dante Pt. 2 - A Conversation with Rachel Jacoff, 2007 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Dante Pt. 3 - A Conversation with Rachel Jacoff, 2007 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Higher Education - A conversation with John Hennessy, 2007 Apr 24; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Ancient Athenian Democracy - A conversation with Josiah Ober, 2007 May 1; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Tom Thomson in Purgatory - A conversation with Troy Jollimore, 2007 May 8; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Hannah Arendt pt. 1 - A conversation with Karen Feldman, 2007 May 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Hannah Arendt pt. 2 - A conversation with Karen Feldman, 2007 May 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Enlightenment - A conversation with Pierre Saint-Amand, 2007 May 22; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Freud & Psychoanalysis Pt 1 - A conversation with Charitini Douvaldzi, 2007 May 29; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Freud & Psychoanalysis Pt 2 - A conversation with Charitini Douvaldzi, 2007 May 29; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Kurt Weill Pt 1 - A conversation with Stephen Hinton, 2007 Jun 5; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Kurt Weill Pt 2 - A conversation with Stephen Hinton, 2007 Jun 5; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Poetry and Thinking in Martin Heidegger- A conversation with Andrew Mitchell, 2007 Jun 12; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Dante and Prufrock - A Coda, 2007 Jun 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - End of the Year Wrap-up, 2007 Jun 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Religion and Violence - Philippe Buc, 2008 Jan 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Orhan Pamuk, 2008 Jan 22; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Pamuk and Modern Turkey - Aron Rodrigue, 2008 Jan 29; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Origins of Agriculture Pt 1 - Michael Shanks, 2008 Feb 5; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Origins of Agriculture Pt 2 - Michael Shanks, 2008 Feb 5; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - History of Psychiatry - Dr. Stewart Agras, 2008 Feb 12; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Vocation of the Humanities - Hayden White, 2008 Feb 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Poetry of A.R. Ammons - Laura Witt, 2008 Feb 26; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Jane Austen - Blakey Vermeule, 2008 Mar 11; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Robert Service - Giovanni Tempesta, 2008 Mar 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - W.B. Yeats - Marjorie Perloff, 2008 Mar 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Boccaccio - Robert Harrison, 2008 Apr 1; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Erwin Schrödinger - Robert Harrison, 2008 Apr 10; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Intellectual History - Paul Robinson, 2008 Sep 24; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - W.H. Auden - Nicholas Jenkins, 2008 Sep 30; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Philosophy of Moods - Hans Ulrich Gumbrecht, 2008 Oct 7; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Persian literature - Dick Davis, 2008 Oct 14; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Heart - Heather Webb and Connie Solari, 2008 Oct 21; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Medical Vocation - Dr. Abraham Verghese, 2008 Oct 28; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Future of the Internet - Vinton Cerf, 2008 Nov 11; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - WWII and the Blitz - Peter Stansky, 2008 Nov 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Human Rights - Helen Stacy, 2008 Nov 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Language and Thought - Lera Boroditsky and Josh Landy, 2008 Nov 4; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Jesuit Order - Matt Farley, 2008 Dec 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Réflexions sur l'Internet - Michel Serres, 2008 Dec 9; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Heart of Darkness - Robert Harrison, 2008 Dec 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Existentialism of Sartre - Lanie Anderson, 2009 Apr 14; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Beethoven Pt 1 - Stephen Hinton, 2009 Apr 21; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Beethoven Pt 2 - Stephen Hinton, 2009 Apr 21; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Romanticism and Organic Form - Denis Gigante, 2009 Apr 28; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Metaphysics of Misogyny - Adrian Daub, 2009 May 5; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Nuance and Brazilian Culture - Maríla Librandi Rocha, 2009 May 12; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Re-enchantment of the World - Michael Saler, 2009 May 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Friedrich Nietzsche - Andrew Mitchell, 2009 May 26; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Byzantine Culture Pt 1 - Panagiotis Agapitos, 2009 Jun 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Byzantine Culture Pt 2 - Panagiotis Agapitos, 2009 Jun 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Emily Dickinson - Katie Peterson, 2009 Jun 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Jimi Hendrix Solo Show, 2009 Jun 20; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Tennis - Dick Gould, 2009 Oct 6; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Unabomber - Jean-Marie Apostolidès, 2009 Oct 6; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Blues - Byrd Hale - Part I, 2009 Oct 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Blues - Byrd Hale - Part II, 2009 Oct 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Borges - Hans Ulrich Gumbrecht, 2009 Nov 23; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Plato - Andrea Nightingale, 2009 Nov 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A Monologue on Machiavelli, 2009 Dec 7; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A Monologue on Wallace Stevens, 2009 Dec 9; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Shakespeare - Stephen Orgel, 2010 Jan 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - American Literature - Tobias Wolff, 2010 Feb 9; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Welsh Literature - Gwyneth Lewis (Part 1), 2010 Feb 16; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Welsh Literature - Gwyneth Lewis (Part 2), 2010 Feb 16; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Digital Music - Jay Kadis, 2010 Feb 23; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Italian Epic Poetry - Giuseppe Mazzotta, 2010 Mar 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Karl Marx - Mark Mancall, 2010 Apr 6; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Athanasius Kircher - Paula Findlen, 2010 Apr 20; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Uses of Literature - Joshua Landy, 2010 Apr 20; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Alexander the Great - Vincent Barletta, 2010 Apr 27; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Glass Wave - Rush Rehm, 2010 May 4; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Pink Floyd - Thomas Harrison, 2010 May 11; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Heidegger's Being and Time - Thomas Sheehan, 2010 May 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Georges Bataille - Laura Wittman, 2010 May 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Doors - Robert Harrison, 2010 Jun 23; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Moby Dick - Andrea Nightingale, 2011 Jan 11; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Classicism in America - Caroline Winterer, 2011 Jan 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Commedia dell'Arte - Mace Perlman, 2011 Jan 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Roberto Bolaño - Héctor Hoyos, 2011 Feb 1; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Romantic Symbol - Nicholas Halmi, 2011 Feb 8; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Uses of Philosophy - John Perry, 2011 Feb 13; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Beauty - Alexander Nehamas (part 1), 2011 Feb 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Beauty - Alexander Nehamas (part 2), 2011 Feb 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Nouveau Roman - Christy Wampole, 2011 Feb 22; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Haitian writer Lyonel Trouillot, 2011 Mar 1; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Aristotle's Poetics - Blair Hoxby, 2011 Mar 8; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Greek Tragedy - Rush Rehm, 2011 Mar 15; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Italian Cinema - Sarah Carey, 2011 Mar 22; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Psychedelic Rock - Jay Kadis, 2011 Mar 29; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Human Brain - Stuart Edelstein, 2011 Apr 5; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Samuel Beckett - Robert Harrison, 2011 Apr 12; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Sonia Korn Grimani and her memoir of the Holocaust, 2011 Apr 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Hiatus Announcement, 2011 Apr 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Phenomenology - Thomas Sheehan, 2011 Oct 5; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Rosetta Stone - Patrick Hunt, 2011 Oct 12; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Hegel and His Heirs - Adrian Daub, 2011 Oct 19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Ancient Roman Family - Richard Saller, 2011 Oct 26; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Life and Poetry of John Keats -Denise Gigante, 2011 Nov 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - The Discipline of Geography - Martin Lewis, 2011 Nov 9; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Homer and Homeric Epics - Richard Martin, 2011 Nov 16; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Medicine and the Human Condition - Larry Zaroff, 2011 Nov 23; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Nietzsche and Wagner - Stephen Hinton, 2011 Nov 30; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Extinction - Ursula Heise, 2012 Apr 11; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Michel Foucault - Hans Sluga, 2012 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - John Rawls - Debra Satz, 2012 Apr 25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Psychological Anthropology - Tanya Luhrmann, 2012 May 2; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Hermaphroditism - Leah DeVun, 2012 May 9; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Life, Literature, Lermontov - Sasha Borovik, 2012 May 16; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Petrarch and Petrarchism - Andrew Hui, 2012 May 23; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - A Brief History of Listening - Gabriella Safran, 2012 May 30; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Post-humanism - Ewa Domanska, 2012 Jun 6; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Chloe Veltman, writer, journalist and radio show host, on the human voice, 2012 Jun 27; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
- Website, 2012 Jun 13; 1812.48 megabyte(s) 441 files in 10 directories